Register to The Karl Weigl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Music by Karl Weigl, I.A
    - Vocal Music
      - Songs
        - [Children's songs]
          - [Children's songs] (Box 5, Folder 138)
            Composers Facsimile Edition, c1958 / American Composers Alliance (New York City).
        - [Children's songs. Texts]
          - Children's songs for Peggy; words by Vera Peters [and] Vally Weigl., 1 item (1 sheet); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 139)
            Texts for "To the Butterfly" and "To Santa Claus."
        - [Cradle song]
          - A Cradle song / Karl Weigl; [text by] Padraic Colum., 1 manuscript score (1 p.); 38 cm. (Box 5, Folder 140)
            "c1974."
            "For tenor" -- in manuscript.
          - [Cradle song] (Box 5, Folder 141)
          - [Cradle song] (Box 5, Folder 142)
            "Transposed from C-sharp to C Major" -- in manuscript.
        - [Duets, soprano, baritone]
          - 5 duets for soprano and baritone = 5 Duette für Sopran und Bariton / Karl Weigl; English translations of the German poems by Vally Weigl. Third song: Composers Facsimile Edition, c1959 / American Composers Alliance (New York City)., 1 manuscript score (18 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 143)
            "Written 1909."
          - [Duets, soprano, baritone] (Box 5, Folder 144)
          - [Duets, soprano, baritone] (Box 5, Folder 145)
            Composers Facsimile Edition, c1959 / American Composers Alliance (New York City).
          - [Duets, soprano, baritone] (Box 5, Folder 146)
          - [Duets, soprano, baritone] (Box 5, Folder 147)
            "Recorded by Colette Boky and George Shirley ..." -- in manuscript.
        - [Early Easter morning]
          - Shouting sun / Karl Weigl; [text by] Nancy [Byrd] Turner., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 40 cm. (Box 31, Folder 1032)
            Author of text written as "Nancy Bird Turner" in caption title.
          - [Early Easter morning] (Box 5, Folder 148)
            Retitled "Early Easter Morning, Halleluja der Sonne = Fruh am Ostermorgen" in manuscript.
          - [Early Easter morning] (Box 31, Folder 1033)
            Retitled "Two Songs of the South, Early Easter Morning, Halleluja der Sonne = Fruh am Ostermorgen" in manuscript.
        - [Folksongs from many lands]
          - Folksongs from many lands / arranged by Karl Weigl. Composers Facsimile Edition / American Composers Alliance (New York City)., 1 manuscript score (20 p.); 36 cm. (Box 5, Folder 149)
        - [Gesänge, op. 1]
          - Sieben Gesänge für Männerstimme und Klavier / komponiert von Karl Weigl. Wien: Universal Edition, c1912., 1 score (25 p.); 32 cm. (Box 5, Folder 150)
            Plate number: U. E. 3586.
            English translations by Vally Weigl, Luise Haessler, and Fred Kaufholz in manuscript.
          - Sieben Gesänge für eine tiefe Männerstimme und Klavier, op. 1 / komponiert von Karl Weigl. Wien: Universal Edition, c1912., 1 score (25 p.); 31 cm. (Box 5, Folder 151)
            English translations by Vally Weigl and Luise Haessler in manuscript.
          - [Gesänge, op. 1] (Box 5, Folder 152)
            Same edition.
            English translation of no. 1 by Vally Weigl in manuscript
          - [Gesänge, op. 1] (Box 5, Folder 153)
            English translation of nos. 1 and 6 in manuscript.
          - [Gesänge, op. 1] (Box 5, Folder 154)
            English translation of nos. 5 and 6 by Vally Weigl in manuscript.
          - [Gesänge, op. 1] (Box 5, Folder 155)
            Photocopy of above edition, without cover or title page.
        - [Gesänge, op. 1. Selections; arr.]
          - Drei Lieder für Mezzosopran oder Alt oder Bariton = Three songs for mezzosoprano or alto or baritone / Karl Weigl; English words by Luise Haessler., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 33 cm. (Box 5, Folder 156)
            Numbers 2, 3, and 7 from Gesänge, op. 1.
            Photocopy of an undated manuscript score
            "c1900."
          - [Gesänge, op. 1. Selections; arr.] (Box 5, Folder 157)
            "c1906."
          - [Gesänge, op. 1. Selections; arr.] (Box 5, Folder 158)
            "c1912."
          - [Gesänge, op. 1. Selections; arr.] (Box 5, Folder 159)
            Reproduced by Independent Music Publishers, New York City.
          - [Gesänge, op. 1. Selections; arr.] (Box 5, Folder 160)
          - Drei Lieder für Mezzosopran oder Alt oder Bariton = Three songs for mezzosoprano or alto or baritone / Karl Weigl; English words by Luise Haessler., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 37 cm. (Box 5, Folder 161)
            Photocopy of an undated manuscript score, c1906.
          - Drei Lieder für Mezzosopran oder Alt oder Bariton = Three songs for mezzosoprano or alto or baritone / Karl Weigl; English words by Luise Haessler., 36 cm. (Box 5, Folder 162)
            "American Composers Alliance Library" -- cover.
        - [Gesänge, op. 1. Ein Gleiches]
          - VI. Ein Gleiches / Karl Weigl; English translation by Vally Weigl., 1 score (1 p.); 31 cm. (Box 5, Folder 163)
            Photocopy from Universal Edition, U. E. 3586, with English translation in manuscript.
        - [Gesänge, op. 1. Texts. English & German]
          - [Texts and notes] (Box 5, Folder 164)
            8 items.
            Includes English translations by Luise Haessler.
        - [Gesänge, alto, piano]
          - 6 Gesänge für tiefe Frauenstimme und Klavier / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (16 p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 165)
            Inscribed to Julius Bittner, Wien, 1934 Apr 9.
          - 6 Gesänge für tiefe Frauenstimme und Klavier / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (16 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 166)
          - 6 Gesänge für tiefe Frauenstimme und Klavier / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (16 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 167)
            "Six songs for contr'alto and piano, English translation by Luise Haessler" -- in manuscript
            English translation is not included.
          - [Gesänge, alto, piano] (Box 6, Folder 168)
            English translation by Luise Haessler in manuscript.
          - [Gesänge, alto, piano] (Box 6, Folder 169)
            Same photocopy, without cover.
          - [Gesänge, alto, piano] (Box 6, Folder 170)
            Composers Facsimile Edition, 1958 / American Composers Alliance (New York City).
        - [Gesänge, alto, piano. Blaue Nacht]
          - Blaue Nacht / [text by] G. Falke., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 26 x 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 171)
            Photocopy of a holograph score, inscribed to Vally Weigl, 1921.
          - No. 6. Blaue Nacht = Blue night / Karl Weigl; [text by] G. Falke; translated into English by Luise Haessler., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 37 cm. (Box 6, Folder 172)
            Photocopy of an undated manuscript score copied by J. Schuller, c1958.
            "Transposed from alto to mezzo" -- in manuscript
          - [Gesänge, alto, piano. Blaue Nacht] (Box 6, Folder 173)
        - [Gesänge, alto, piano. Texts. English & German]
          - [Texts] (Box 6, Folder 174)
            "Translated into English by Luise Haessler," 1941 Sep.-Nov., n.d.
        - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet]
          - Three songs for contr'alto and string quartet / by Karl Weigl; English words by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl. Composers Facsimile Edition, c1958 / American Composers Alliance (New York City)., 1 manuscript score (16 p.) + 4 manuscript parts; 36 cm. (Box 6, Folder 175)
            Photocopy of an undated manuscript score and parts.
          - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet] (Box 6, Folder 176)
            Same photocopy as above (score only).
          - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet] (Box 6, Folder 177)
            General Music Publishing, c19-- (Hastings-on-Hudson, New York).
          - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet] (Box 6, Folder 178)
        - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet. Vocal score]
          - Drei Gesänge für eine tiefe Frauenstimme und Streichquartett / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (17 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 179)
            Klavierauszug.
            Arranged for voice and piano.
            Includes English words by Lydia Perera.
            Undated holograph score, signed.
          - Sommers Tod; Liebesode; Hexenlied., 1 manuscript score (18 p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 180)
          - 3 Gesänge für Altstimme und Streichquartett / von Karl Weigl = Three songs for contr'alto and string quartet / by Karl Weigl; English translation by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl. Composers Facsimile Edition, c1958 / American Composers Alliance (New York City)., 1 manuscript score (16 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 181)
          - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet. Vocal score] (Box 6, Folder 182)
          - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet. Vocal score] (Box 6, Folder 183)
            Pioneer Editions (New York City).
        - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet. Parts]
          - 3 Gesänge für Altstimme und Streichquartett = Three songs for contr'alto and string quartet / Karl Weigl., 4 manuscript parts; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 184)
            Set of undated manuscript string quartet parts.
        - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet. Texts]
          - [Texts] (Box 6, Folder 185)
            1 item.
            In manuscript, n.d.
        - [Gesänge, alto, string quartet. Texts. English]
          - [Texts] (Box 6, Folder 186)
            3 items.
            Includes translations by Vally Weigl.
        - [Gesänge, mezzo-soprano, string quartet]
          - Three songs for mezzo-soprano and string quartet / Karl Weigl. Composers Facsimile Edition, c1958 / American Composers Alliance (New York City)., 1 manuscript score (13 p.) + 4 ms parts; 36 cm. (Box 6, Folder 189)
            Photocopy of an undated manuscript score and set of string quartet parts.
            Includes English translation by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl.
            General Music Publishing, c19-- (New York City).
          - [Gesänge, mezzo-soprano, string quartet] (Box 6, Folder 190)
            Same photocopy as above (parts only).
          - [Gesänge, mezzo-soprano, string quartet] (Box 6, Folder 191)
            Same photocopy, without score.
        - [Gesänge, mezzo-soprano, string quartet. Vocal score]
          - Three songs for mezzo soprano and string quartet / Karl Weigl. Composers Facsimile Edition, c1958 / American Composers Alliance (New York City)., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 35 cm. + 4 ms parts; 37 cm. (Box 6, Folder 192)
            Score arranged for voice and piano.
        - [Gesänge, mezzo-soprano, string quartet. Texts, English]
          - [Texts] (Box 6, Folder 193)
            "English translation by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl."
            Typescript, mimeograph, n.d.
        - [Gesänge aus Phantasus]
          - Fünf Gesänge aus Phantasus: für eine hohe Stimme und Klavier: op. 9 / von Karl Weigl; [text by] Arno Holz. S.l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (16 p.); 31 cm. (Box 6, Folder 194)
            Title from cover.
            English translation by Vally Weigl and Jacqueline Parsons in manuscript.
            Publisher's no.: 34.
            Publisher's plate no.: E. ST. 34.
          - [Gesänge aus Phantasus] (Box 6, Folder 195)
          - [Gesänge aus Phantasus] (Box 6, Folder 196)
            "Five songs from Phantasus: for a high voice with piano: op. 9 / by Karl Weigl; [text by] Arno Holz; English words by Vally Weigl" -- in manuscript.
          - [Gesänge aus Phantasus] (Box 6, Folder 197)
            Photocopy of above edition
            "c1905."
          - [Gesänge aus Phantasus] (Box 6, Folder 198)
        - [Gesänge aus Phantasus. Texts.]
          - [Texts] (Box 6, Folder 199)
            Typescript, carbon, n.d.
        - [Gesänge aus Phantasus. Texts. English]
          - [Texts] (Box 6, Folder 200)
            Translations by Vally Weigl.
        - [Gesprache mit dem Tode]
          See [Weltfeier. Gesprach mit dem Tode. Vocal score] in Cantatas
        - [Glorious vagabond]
          - The glorious hobo / Karl Weigl; [text] by Charlotte Storm., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 7, Folder 201)
          - [Glorious vagabond] (Box 7, Folder 202)
            Title changed to "The Glorious Hobo" in manuscript.
          - [Glorious vagabond] (Box 7, Folder 203)
            "1939, New York" -- in manuscript.
        - [Graue Jahre]
          - Graue Jahre = Grey years / Karl Weigl; [text by] Lilly Rona; English words by Vally Weigl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 204)
          - [Graue Jahre] (Box 7, Folder 205)
            "c1942."
        - [Invisible light]
          - The invisible light / [text] by Johanna Frada; Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 7, Folder 206)
            Version for high voice.
          - [Invisible light] (Box 7, Folder 207)
            Same photocopy, with German translation by Vally Weigl.
          - [Invisible light] (Box 7, Folder 208)
          - [Invisible light] (Box 7, Folder 209)
          - The invisible light = Das unsichtbare Licht / Karl Weigl; English poem by Johanna Frada; German translation by Vally Weigl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 7, Folder 210)
            Version for low voice.
          - [Invisible light], 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 7, Folder 212)
            The invisible light = Das unsichtbare Licht / Karl Weigl; English poem by Johanna Frada; German translation by Vally Weigl.
            Photocopy of an undated manuscript score, c1974.
        - [Kinderlieder]
          - Kinderlieder: für eine Singstimme und Klavier: op. 11 / von Karl Weigl. Wein: Ed. Strache, c1924., 1 score (14 p.); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 213)
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 214)
            English translation by Ronald V. Smith in manuscript.
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 215)
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 216)
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 217)
            English translation by Ronald V. Smith and Vally Weigl in manuscript.
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 218)
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 219)
          - [Kinderlieder] (Box 7, Folder 220)
        - [Kinderlieder. English]
          - Seven songs of children: op. 11 / by Karl Weigl; translated from the German of Klaus Groth and Des Knaben Wunderhorn by Ronald V. Smith., 1 manuscript score (16 p.); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 221)
            Title changed to "Children's Songs (for Maria)".
        - [Liebeslied]
          - Liebeslied / Karl Weigl; Gedicht von H. F. Schell; English translation by Vally Weigl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 222)
          - Liebeslied = Love song / Karl Weigl; Gedicht von H. F. Schell; English translation by Vally Weigl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 7, Folder 223)
          - [Liebeslied] (Box 7, Folder 224)
          - [Liebeslied] (Box 7, Folder 225)
            Same photocopy
          - Liebeslied = Love song / Karl Weigl; Gedicht von H. F. Schell; English translation by Vally Weigl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 37 cm. (Box 7, Folder 226)
            " c1958."
          - [Liebeslied] (Box 7, Folder 227)
        - [Liebeslieder]
          - Liebes-Lieder: für hohe Singstimme und Klavier: Opus 22 / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (18 p.); 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 228)
            Version including "Mailied" (no. 5).
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 229)
            Includes English translation in manuscript.
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 230)
            Includes English translation by Vally Weigl in manuscript.
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 231)
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 232)
            Same photocopy as above with English translation by Vally Weigl and dedication "To our dear children, Etta Ruth and Johnny, for their We-Day," 1946 Aug 20.
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 233)
            Version including "Abendgang" (no. 5).
            Inlcudes English translation by Vally Weigl in manuscript.
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 234)
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 235)
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 236)
            Same photocopy with English translation by Vally Weigl and dedication "To our dear children, Etta Ruth and Johnny, for their We-Day," 1946 Aug 20.
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 237)
          - [Liebeslieder] (Box 7, Folder 238)
        - [Liebeslieder. Liebeslied]
          - Frühling / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 239)
            Version in B-sharp Major.
          - Liebeslied., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 240)
            Photocopy, incomplete, from an undated manuscript score.
            "c1968."
        - [Liebeslieder. Phönix]
          - Der Phönix / Karl Weigl., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 241)
            Version in D Major.
        - [Liebeslieder. Texts. English]
          - [Texts] (Box 7, Folder 242)
            Manuscript and typescript, n.d.
            Also includes "Der Vogel" from "Lieder nach Gedichten von O.J. Bierbaum"
        - [Liedchen des Bürgermeisters]
          See [Rattenfänger von Hameln. Liedchen des Bürgermeisters] in Operas
        - [Lieder, op. 3]
          - Fünf Lieder für hohe Männerstimme und Klavier, op. 3 / von Karl Weigl. Wien: Universal Edition, c1910., 1 score (13 p.); 32 cm. (Box 7, Folder 243)
            Publisher's no.: 2976.
            Plate no.: U. E. 2976.
          - [Lieder, op. 3] (Box 7, Folder 244)
            English translation by Vally Weigl, 1981, in manuscript.
          - [Lieder, op. 3] (Box 7, Folder 245)
          - [Lieder, op. 3] (Box 7, Folder 246)
            "Theodore Presser Co., sole agents."
        - [Lieder, op. 3. Pfingstlied]
          - [Lieder, op. 3. Pfingstlied] (Box 7, Folder 247)
            Photocopy of an excerpt from Universal Edition, U. E. 2976.
        - [Lieder, op. 3. Fraue, du Süsse]
          - [Lieder, op. 3. Fraue, du Süsse] (Box 7, Folder 248)
        - [Lieder, op. 3. Texts. English & German]
          - [Texts] (Box 7, Folder 249)
            5 items.
            "Translated into English by Luise Haessler," 1941 Jul.-Oct.
        - [Lieder, op. 8. Elfen sangen]
          - Die Elfen sangen = The fairies sang: op. 8, No. 1 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Goethe. Leipzig: Rob. Forberg, c1914., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 250)
            "Künstler-Exemplar" - stamp.
        - [Lieder, op. 8. Juli]
          - Juli = July: op. 8, No. 2 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Th. Storm. Leipzig: Rob. Forberg, c1914., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 251)
          - [Lieder, op. 8. Juli] (Box 8, Folder 252)
            Stamped on cover with Star of David.
          - [Lieder, op. 8. Juli] (Box 8, Folder 253)
        - [Lieder, op. 8. Gode Nacht]
          - Gode Nacht = Good night: op. 8, No. 3 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Th. Storm. Leipzig: Rob. Forberg, c1914., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 254)
          - [Lieder, op. 8. Gode Nacht] (Box 8, Folder 255)
            Same edition as above.
          - [Lieder, op. 8. Gode Nacht] (Box 8, Folder 256)
            Cover only of Same edition.
        - [Lieder, op. 8. Marienlied]
          - Marienlied = Song to Mary: op. 8, No. 4 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Novalis. Leipzig: Rob. Forberg, c1914., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 257)
          - Marienlied / Karl Weigl; [text by] Novalis., 1 score (1 p.); 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 258)
            Photocopy of an undated printed score with manuscript English translation by Ada Rosenthal.
        - [Lieder, op. 8. Schlummerliedchen]
          - Schlummerliedchen = Lullaby: op. 8, No. 5 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Rich. Leander. Leipzig: Rob. Forberg, c1914., 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 259)
          - [Lieder, op. 8. Schlummerliedchen] (Box 8, Folder 260)
        - [Lieder, op. 10]
          - 5 Lieder für eine tiefere Frauenstimme / Karl Weigl., 1 score (14 p.); 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 261)
            Photocopy of published scores (Edition Strache), with English translations by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl.
            "c1913" and "c1974."
          - [Lieder, op. 10] (Box 8, Folder 262)
        - [Lieder, op. 10. Selections]
          - Der toten Mutter; Jesus; Fremd geh ich unter den Fremden; O Nacht, du silberbleiche., 1 score (10 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 263)
            Consists of published scores (Edition Strache), with English translations by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl.
            English words for "Fremd geh ich unter den Fremden" in manuscript.
          - 3 songs for contralto or mezzo soprano = 3 Lieder für eine tiefere stimme / Karl Weigl. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (8 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 264)
            Includes "Der toten Mutter," "Jesus," and O Nacht, du silberbleiche."
            English translations by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl.
            Plate nos.: E. St. 229, E. St. 228, E. St. 331.
          - 3 songs for contralto or mezzo soprano = 3 Lieder für eine tiefere Stimme / Karl Weigl. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (fragment); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 265)
            T. p. and first page of music only.
          - Märchen; Jesus., 1 printed and manuscript score (8 p.); 37 cm. (Box 8, Folder 266)
            Consists of a photocopy of Märchen (Edition Strache, n.d.) and a photocopy of a transposed version of Jesus, undated manuscript.
        - [Lieder, op. 10. Märchen]
          - Märchen: op. 10, Nr. 1 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Herm. Runge. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 267)
            Publisher's no.: 32.
            Plate no.: E. St. 227.
          - [Lieder, op. 10. Märchen] (Box 8, Folder 268)
            English translation by Vally Weigl in manuscript and typescript.
          - [Lieder, op. 10. Märchen] (Box 8, Folder 269)
            "Auslieferung, Julius Schwedler" - back cover.
          - [Lieder, op. 10. Märchen] (Box 8, Folder 270)
            Photocopy of above edition with English translation by Vally Weigl, without cover.
            Composers Facsimile Edition, c1966 / American Composers Alliance (New York City).
        - [Lieder, op. 10. Jesus]
          - Jesus: op. 10, Nr. 2 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Peter Baum. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 271)
            Plate no.: E. St. 228.
          - Jesus: op. 10, Nr. 2 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Peter Baum; English words by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 272)
            Pages numbered 4-6.
          - Jesus: op. 10, Nr. 2 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Peter Baum; English words by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 273)
            Transposed version.
        - [Lieder, op. 10. Toten Mutter]
          - Der toten Mutter: op. 10, Nr. 3 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Paul Grotowsky. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 274)
            Plate no.: E. St. 229.
          - [Lieder, op. 10. Toten Mutter] (Box 8, Folder 275)
            Photocopy of above edition with English translation by Lydia Perera and Vally Weigl, without title page.
        - [Lieder, op. 10. Fremd geh ich unter den Fremden]
          - Fremd geh ich unter den Fremden: op. 10, Nr. 4 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Walter Calé. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 276)
            Plate no.: E. St. 230.
          - [Lieder, op. 10. Fremd geh ich unter den Fremden] (Box 8, Folder 277)
          - [Lieder, op. 10. Fremd geh ich unter den Fremden] (Box 8, Folder 278)
            Photocopy of above edition with English translation by Vally Weigl
            "c1913."
        - [Lieder, op. 10. O Nacht, du silberbleiche]
          - O Nacht, du silberbleiche: op. 10, Nr. 5 / Karl Weigl; [text by] Herm. Hesse. S. l.: Edition Strache, n.d., 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 279)
            Plate no.: E. St. 231.